dynamicmessenger.com 2006-10-17

# Alterian - Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting our website, which is brought to you by Alterian. This Privacy Policy tells you how we collect, use, and disclose personally identifiable information that you provide via this web site. Please be sure to read this entire Privacy Policy before using or submitting information to this site. This site is intended for use by residents of the United Kingdom. 

**Your Consent**  
By using this site, you agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy. Whenever you submit information via this site, you consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

****

**Active Information Collection**  
Like many web sites, this site actively collects information from its visitors both by asking you specific questions and by permitting you to communicate directly with us via e-mail and feedback forms. Some of the information that you submit may be personally identifiable information (that is, information that can be uniquely identified with you, such as your full name, address, e-mail address, phone number, and so on). Some areas of this site may require you to submit information in order for you to benefit from the specified features (e.g. a newsletter subscription) or participate in a particular activity (such as a poll or other questionnaire). You will be informed at each information collection point what information is required and what information is optional. Please be aware, however, that if you decide not to provide that information, you may not be able to use some of the user convenience features of this website. 

Alterian collects registration information so we can contact you about updates to our product range and information that we feel may interest you. Although we retain registration records, you can choose to not receive future mailings from Alterian by selecting the appropriate box on all communications and responses. 

****

**Passive Information Collection**  
As you navigate through a website, certain information can be passively collected (that is, gathered without your actively providing the information) using various technologies and means, such as Internet Protocol addresses, cookies, Internet tags, and navigational data collection. We use Internet Protocol (IP) addressees on this site. 

A 'Cookie' is a bit of information that a website sends to your web browser that helps the site remember information about you and your preferences.   
'Session' cookies are temporary bits of information that are erased once you exit your Web browser window or otherwise turn your computer off. Session cookies are used to improve navigation on web sites and to collect aggregate statistical information. This site does not use session cookies. 

'Persistent' cookies are more permanent bits of information that are placed on the hard drive of your computer and stay there unless you delete the cookie. Persistent cookies store information on your computer for a number of purposes, such as retrieving certain information you have previously provided (e.g. login passwords), helping to determine what areas of the Web site visitors find most valuable, and customising the web site based on your preferences. This site uses persistent cookies. 

'Internet tags' (also known as single-pixel GIF's, clear GIF's, invisible GIF's, and 1-by-1 GIF's) are smaller than cookies and tell the web site server information such as the IP address and browser type related to the visitor's computer. We use Internet tags at this site. 

Tags have been placed both on online advertisements that bring people to the site and on different pages of the site. These tags indicate how many times a page is opened and which information is consulted. We do not collect or seek personally identifiable information through these tags. 

Responses to polls conducted on this site are pooled anonymously to provide aggregate results. 'Navigational data' ('log files', 'server logs', and 'clickstream' data) are used for system management, to improve the content of the site, market research purposes, and to communicate information to visitors. This site uses navigational data. 

****

**Use and Disclosure of Information**  
Except as otherwise stated, we may use your information to improve the content of our site, to customise the site to your preferences, to communicate information to you (if you have requested it), for our marketing and research purposes, and for the purposes specified in this Privacy Policy. 

If you provide personally identifiable information to this site, we may combine such information with other actively collected information unless we specify otherwise at the point of collection. We will take reasonable measures to prevent personally identifiable information from being combined with passively collected information, unless you consent otherwise. 

We may disclose your personally identifiable information to other Alterian affiliates worldwide that agree to treat it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. In addition, we may disclose your personally identifiable information to third parties, located in the UK and/or any other country, but only: 

To contractors we use to support our business (e.g. fulfilment services, technical support), in which case we will require such third parties to agree to treat it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

In connection with the sale, assignment, or other transfer of the business of this site to which the information relates, in which case we will require any such buyer to agree to treat It in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

Where required by applicable laws, court orders, or government regulations. In addition, we will make full use of information acquired through this site that is not in personally identifiable form. 

****

**Access and Correction**  
You can at any time correct your personal profile by responding in the 'Contact Details' section. To keep your personally identifiable information accurate, current, and compete, please contact us as specified below. We will take reasonable steps to update or correct personally identifiable information in our possession that you have previously submitted via this site. 

****

**Security**  
We take reasonable steps to protect your personally identifiable information as you transmit your information from your computer to our site and to protect such information from loss, misuse, and unauthorised access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. You should keep in mind that no Internet transmission is ever 100% secure or error-free. In particular, e-mail sent to or from this site may not be secure, and you should therefore take special care in deciding what information you send to us via e-mail. Moreover, where you use passwords, ID numbers, or other special features on this site, it is your responsibility to safeguard them. 

****

**Links to Other Web Sites**  
This site may contain links or references to other web sites that we do not control and to which our Privacy Policy does not apply. Please be sure that you read the privacy policy of every website you visit. You are solely responsible for your interactions with such websites. 

****

**How to Contact Us  
** If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Policy or the information practices of this site. Please contact us as follows: 

Helen Harris  
Marketing Manager  
Alterian plc  
Century Place  
Newfoundland Street  
Bristol  
BS2 9AG

Tel: +44 117 970 3200  
Fax: +44 117 970 3201

 ****

 **Changes to this Privacy Policy**   
If this Privacy Policy changes, the revised policy will be posted on this site. Please check back periodically, and especially before you provide any personally identifiable information.

This Privacy Policy was last updated in July 2002.
